Fully Awesome.
Bolt is a animation, family, adventure film directed by Chris Williams.
Bolt is the star of the biggest show in Hollywood.
The only problem is, he thinks it's real.
After he's accidentally shipped to New York City and separated from Penny, his beloved
co-star and owner, Bolt must harness all his "super powers" to find a way home.
Bolt (voice), played by John Travolta.
Penny (voice), played by Miley Cyrus.
Mittens (voice), played by Susie Essman.
Rhino (voice), played by Mark Walton.
Dr. Calico (voice), played by Malcolm McDowell.
The Director (voice), played by James Lipton.
Bolt is a 2008 American animated adventure comedy film
produced by Walt Disney Animation Studios.
It was directed by Chris Williams and Byron Howard, written by Williams and Dan
Fogelman, and features the voices of John Travolta and Miley Cyrus.
The film's plot centers on a dog named Bolt (Travolta), who has spent his entire life on
the set of a television series and firmly believes that he has superpowers.
Bolt premiered at the El Capitan Theatre in Hollywood, Los Angeles, on November 17, 2008, and
was released in the United States on November 21, by Walt Disney Pictures.
The film received positive reviews from critics and grossed
$310 million against a $150 million budget.
It is regarded as helping to instigate a rebirth of Walt Disney Animation Studios, setting the studio in a new
creative direction that led to other critically acclaimed features such as Tangled (2010) and Frozen (2013).
The film was nominated for several awards, including the Academy Award and the Golden Globe
for Best Animated Feature, and Golden Globe Award for Best Original Song.
The film explores themes of hamster, human animal
relationship, talking dog, animals, cat vs dog.
The tone is lighthearted.